A Guide to the JMU Nursing Department Records, 1951-2015 (bulk 1972- 2001): UA 0006
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Nursing Department Records,
1951-2015 (bulk 1972-2001)
Special Collections, James Madison University
JMU School of Nursing
UA 0006
8.26 cubic feet; 23 boxes
Consists of meeting minutes, correspondence, studies, grants, photographs, and scrapbooks documenting the creation and growth of the Department of Nursing at James Madison University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research with the exception of the files marked as restricted in the inventory below. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the JMU Nursing Department in November 2013 after Erica Lewis, then Assistant Professor in the Department of Nursing, found several boxes labeled "nursing history" in the basement in a storage room near her office. Another portion of the collection was transferred to Special Collections in December 2016 by Michele Dombrowski, Outreach Coordinator in the School of Nursing. In August 2018, an addition was transferred consisting of multiple Nursing Student Association scrapbooks, loose photos, and records.
Administrative History
Prior to the development of a nursing program, Madison College offered pre-nursing courses to students who then transferred to other baccalaureate nursing programs. Interest in developing a full baccalaureate degree program began to increase in the 1960s, when a national trend of hospital nursing school closures came to Harrisonburg when the Rockingham Memorial Hospital (RMH) School of Nursing officially closed in 1970.
In May 1972, Madison College President, Dr. Ronald E. Carrier, submitted a proposal to the State Council of Higher Education in Virginia (SCHEV) to develop a nursing program at the College. It was not until 1979 that SCHEV granted permission to activate the program. Dr. Marcia Dake was appointed the fourth director, later dean, of Nursing Education in July 1979 and served in this role until 1988. The first students entered the program in the fall of 1980 and 21 of these students made up the first graduating class in spring 1982.
In fall 1982, the Department of Nursing received full accreditation from the National League for Nursing (NLN). After reorganization within the university, the department joined the new College of Health and Human Development in 1988, later merging with the College of Health and Behavioral Studies in 1994. Opting for new accreditation at the end of the 1990s, the department was granted full accreditation by the newly formed Commission on Collegiate Nursing Education (CCNE) in April 1999. In collaboration with Eastern Mennonite University's Nursing Program, the department was granted the Pi Mu at-large chapter of Sigma Theta Tau, International (STTI) Nursing Honor Society in 2000.
Expanding on the nursing program, the department implemented a new Master of Science degree with nurse practitioner and nurse educator concentrations in 2004, with the first cohort graduating in 2006. The department received full 10-year reaccreditation of all programs from the CCNE in 2009. In 2010, SCHEV granted approval for the development of a Doctor of Nursing Practice (DNP) program at JMU. In 2013, the Department of Nursing implemented online learning for the DNP and RN-BSN programs. The department also operates a Chronic Illness minor open to all undergraduate students.
Scope and Content
The JMU Nursing Department Records, 1951-2015 (bulk 1972-2001), consists of 20 boxes documenting the creation and growth of nursing at JMU. This collection contains scrapbooks, documents, letters, studies, and photographs that helped spark the interest for a nursing program at Madison College in 1951. Proposals for new curriculums, order forms for uniforms, photographs of graduating classes and faculty, newspaper and magazine articles discussing student nurses, are all included within the collection. Other materials include faculty business minutes, grants for training and special projects, budget documents, correspondence between staff and students (letters and emails), nursing program policies, and information on pinning ceremonies held by the department. Please note that some folders are restricted and are marked in the inventory below. These folders are restricted due to individual student records.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following 5 series:
Series 1: Faculty, 1975-2014 (bulk 1975-2001) Series 2: Grants, 1972-1981 Series 3: Subject Files, 1951-2015 Series 4: Photographs, 1980-2015 (bulk 1982-1999) Series 5: Scrapbooks, 2000-2007
Series 1: Faculty, 1975-2014 (bulk 1975-2001) Series 4: Photographs, 1980-2015 (bulk 1982-1999), and Series 5: Scrapbooks, 2000-2007 are arranged chronologically. Series 2: Grants, 1972-1981 and Series 3: Subject Files, 1951-2000 are arranged alphabetically.
Bibliography
School of Nursing History as found in the Collection Control File.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Education, Higher -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- History; James Madison University. School of Nursing -- History; James Madison University. Department of Nursing -- History; James Madison University -- History; Madison College -- History; Nursing -- Study and teaching
Genre and Form Terms:
Minutes (administrative records); Letters; CD-ROMS; DVDs; Grant Proposals; Photographs; Photograph albums; Scrapbooks; Newspaper clippings; Proposals
- Faculty, 1975-2014 (bulk 1975-2001)
  Scope and Content
  Arranged chronologically.
  Series 1: Faculty, 1975-2014 (bulk 1975-2001) is arranged chronologically and consists primarily of administrative business and curriculum documents within the nursing department covering the years 1975-2001. The majority of information contained in these documents relates to faculty planning meeting minutes, in which they discuss prospectuses for new curriculum, meetings about classes, and course descriptions. There are also memos and correspondence that discuss the details of the nursing program, upcoming classes, and potential field trips as well as weekly updates to the nursing department staff. Also included are three items of interest relating to Dr. Marcia Dake, Dean of the Nursing Department. These include a DVD (pending reformatting) titled, Marcia Dake: A Transition, dealing with assisted living, notes from a 2005 interview with her, and memos and correspondence form her retirement as Department Head in 1988.
  - Faculty Minutes, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting, Nursing 480-481, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting, Nursing 380-381, Fall 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes- Nursing, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes- Nursing Division, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting for Self Study Report, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting Junior Level (380 series),, Fall 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting Nursing 390-391, Spring 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting Nursing 490, 491, Spring 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Meeting- Junior Level, Fall 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting- Senior Level, Spring 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes- Nursing, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Minutes- Curriculum, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - College of Nursing Faculty Minutes & Memos, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Meeting- Senior Level Fall, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Faculty Meeting- Junior Level, Fall 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting- Senior Level, Spring 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Faculty Planning Meeting- Junior Level, Spring 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Meeting & Curriculum, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Meeting- Curriculum, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Meeting- Senior Level, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Faculty Minutes- Alumni Steering Committee, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting- Senior Level, Fall 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Faculty Meeting- Senior Level, Spring 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Access Restrictions
    Privacy protected information may be revealed during use of this file. Researchers agree to make no notes or other recordation of privacy protected information found within this file, and further agree not to publish or disclose such information for any purpose.
  - College of Nursing Minutes/Memos, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Meeting- Curriculum, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - culty Meeting- Senior Level, Fall 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Faculty Meeting- Junior Level, Fall 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes Senior Level, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Faculty Meeting- Curriculum, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Faculty Meeting- Nursing, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - College of Nursing Faculty Minutes, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Memos and Correspondence with Judy Holt, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Meeting- Curriculum, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Minutes Department, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes- Senior, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Marcia Dake Retirement, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Vida Huber Department Head Memo, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Meeting- Junior, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Meeting- Senior, 1988, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Weekly, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1991-1993, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Weekly, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Judy Holt Miscellaneous, 1997, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Weekly Updates, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Weekly Updates, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Marcia Dake Interview Notes, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Marcia Dake: A Transition DVD, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Grants, 1972-1981
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Series 2: Grants, 1972-1981, includes grants that were awarded to the nursing program, including a capitation grant, a Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (DHEW) grant; a Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW) grant; a special project grant; and various training grants. Grant application forms and approval forms are also included. The Capitation Grant, given to the program for the years 1980-1982, assisted with training nurses. In 1977, the Department of Nursing wrote a final progress report to DHEW asking them for approval to develop a baccalaureate nursing program at Madison College in order to replace the discontinued RMH program. The remaining grants in this series relate to the development of the nursing school and obtaining funding for the program. Along with grants and proposals, this series also includes miscellaneous letters of correspondence between Madison College faculty and employees of departments that distributed funding.
  - Capitation Grant, 1979 (1980) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - D.H.E.W. Grant Final Report, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Grant Approval Forms, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Grants and Internal Business, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - H.E.W., 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - H.E.W. Grant Proposal (Folder 1 of 2), 1973, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - H.E.W. Grant Proposal (Folder 2 of 2), 1973, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - H.E.W. Grant Proposal, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - H.E.W. Grant Proposal, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - H.E.W. Grant Proposal, 1972, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - H.E.W. Training Grant Application (Folder 1 of 2), 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - H.E.W. Training Grant Application (Folder 2 of 2), 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Implementation of BSN Program Special Project Grant, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Proposal, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Nursing Capitation Grant Forms, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Special Project Grant, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Training Grant, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Subject Files, 1951-2015
  Series 3: Subject Files, 1951-2015, is the largest in the collection. Materials include budgets, course descriptions, six-year plans, and contracts. Additionally, there are many documents concerning the Career Days event held yearly by the Nursing Department. These materials include letters written by JMU staff inviting different hospitals or nursing facilities to attend and speak with juniors and seniors about possible job opportunities and real-life nursing experience. Other materials include lists of graduating students and commencement bulletins for the years 1982-1986. Along with course syllabi, course requirements, and student policies, this series also contains College of Nursing Newsletters. Correspondence between faculty members, photographs (1990-1998), and articles concerning nursing students are included along with pinning ceremony documents.
  Although there are photographs in this series, the majority of photographs can be found in Series 4: Photographs, 1980-2015 (bulk 1982-1999).
  - Accreditation Work, 1989, 1993-1994, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Allied Health Professions, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 1975-1976, 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Budget Printouts, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bulletin: Department of Nursing, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Career Day, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Career Day, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Career Day, October 12, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Career Fair, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Catalog Descriptions of courses offered in Nursing, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Class Materials, 1998, 1999, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - College of Nursing Newsletter, 1985, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Commencement, May 8, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Commencement, Class of 1983, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Commencement, Spring and Summer, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Commencement, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Commencement, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Commencement, Spring and Summer, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Curriculum and Instruction, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Studies, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Community/Clinical Experiences, Spring, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Community/Clinical Experiences, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Community/Clinical Experiences, Fall 1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Community/Clinical Experiences, Spring 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Community/Clinical Experiences, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Community/Clinical Experiences, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Consultants: Fees, Reports, Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Contracts between Businesses/Hospitals for Clinical/Community Experiences, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Convocation for College of Nursing, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Copies, Resumes, EMU, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence between Dr. Dake and others, 1979, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Council of Baccalaureate and Higher Degree Nursing Programs Survey, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Course Descriptions, 1980-1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Course Outlines, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Course Outlines, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Course Syllabus, Spring 1982, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Course Syllabus, Fall 1982, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Course Syllabus, Spring 1983, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Course Syllabus, Spring 1984, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Course Syllabus, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Course Proposals: Department of Nursing, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Course Proposals, Nursing Program, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Course Proposals: Submitted to C & I Committee, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum Plan, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum: Proposed Curriculum: Course Descriptions, Outlines, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Data Regarding Appeal to SCHEV (7/18/77),, 1975, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Department Chairmen JMU, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Department of Nursing Bag, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Description of Program, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Developing the Nursing Program at Madison College, 1972, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dunham_Bush, 1976-1977, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - EMC Educational Consortium, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - EMC Continuing Education Nursing Survey, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Establishing the B.S. in Nursing, (Folder 1 of 2), 1957, 1961, 1969, 1972-1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Establishing the B.S. in Nursing, (Folder 2 of 2), 1957, 1961, 1969, 1972-1978 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Evaluation: Statement, Clinical Evaluation, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Feasibility of Establishing Madison School of Nursing, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Gardner, Dr. Joseph, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Get Well Cards- Blank, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Grant, E. Louise Personal, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Guestbook, 1982-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - History (Folder 1 of 3), 1973-1999 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - History (Folder 2 of 3), 1973-1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - History (Folder 3 of 3), 1973-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - History of Madison College Nursing Program (Folder 1 of 2), 1958-1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - History of Madison College Nursing Program (Folder 2 of 2), 1958-1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Honors Day, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Inventory of Nursing Program Furniture and Equipment, 1976-1980, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - JMU and UVA Miscellaneous, 1977-1978, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Locations and Businesses used in Clinical/Community Experiences, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Minutes, Notes, etc., 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Madison College Baccalaureate Degree Program in Nursing, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Materials prepared for Nursing Department, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Marketing Proposal for UVA School of Nursing, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - News Articles- Various, 1997, 2000, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1977, 1982, 2015, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Nursing 290, 380, 381, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Nursing 390, 391, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Nursing 480, 481, 490, 491, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Nursing Charms/Pins, 1981-1996 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Nursing Program Chronology, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Nursing Equipment, 1974-1980 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Nursing Faculty Responsibilities, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Nursing Program, 1951 (Folder 1 of 2), 1972-1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Nursing Program, 1951 (Folder 2 of 2), 1951, 1972-1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Nursing Program, 1973-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Nursing Student Policies (Folder 1 of 2), 1980-1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Nursing Student Policies (Folder 2 of 2), 1980-1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Nursing Survey of Needs, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Organizational Chart- JMU, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Orientation: Pre-Nursing, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Original RN Proposal Information, 1979, 1982-1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Class of 1987 -1988 Photos and Pinning Ceremony, 1990-1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Class of 1987-1988 Photos and Pining Ceremony, 1990-1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Pinning, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Pinning, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Pinning, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Pinning, 1984, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Pinning, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Pinning, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Pinning, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Pinning, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Pinning, 1987-1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Pinning, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Pinning, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Pinning, 1988, 1991-1993, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Pinning, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Pinning, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Pinning, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Pinning, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pinning, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Pinning, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Pinning, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Pinning, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Pinning, 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Pinning Ceremony Programs, 1982-1998, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy of Nursing/ Nursing Program Objectives, 1976, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Position Statements, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Pre- Nursing List, 1975, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Pre- Nursing Orientation, Dr. Gallagher, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Program, Various, 1976-1977, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Programs, 1984, 1997, 1999, 2000, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Program Proposal: BSN & Interoffice Communication, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Program Proposal: BSN Prepared for State Council, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Program Proposal: BSN Dr. Gallagher Copy, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Program Proposal/ Correspondence, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Program Proposal: SCHEV, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Program Proposal to SCHEV, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Program Proposal: Revised Proposal to SCHEV, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Program Proposal: SCHEV, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Prospectus Baccalaureate Nursing Program, September 1976 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Prospectus, Fall 1976, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Prospectus Final Edits, Submitted Jan. 1977, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Prospectus, Oct. 1976, Board of Nursing, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Prospectus Report to Virginia State Board of Nursing, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Publicity, 1981, 1985, 1989, 1999, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Recruitment Fair, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Record of Acquisitions, Complementary Copies, & Publications for Nursing Department, 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Responses to Manpower Study, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - RMH Historical Information, M. Snyder, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - RN Education Plan, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - RN Pilot Project, 1980-1982, 1984-1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - RN Program, 1986-1990 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Rockingham Memorial Hospital, (Folder 1 of 2), 1975, 1979-1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Rockingham Memorial Hospital, (Folder 2 of 2), 1975, 1979-1996 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Rockingham Memorial Hospital Transition, 1974-1977, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Rotations and Other Documents, 1977, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - SACS, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - SCHE, 1972-1977, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - SCHE: Appeal for B.S.N. Program, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - SCHE: Appeal for B.S.N. Program & Attachments, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - SCHE: Letter of Intent, 1972, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - SCHE: Progress Report, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - SCHEV Letter & Wine Price Renovation, 1978, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Self-Evaluation, 1992, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Semester Objectives, 1983, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Six-Year Plan for the School of Nursing, 1982-1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Six-Year Plan for the School of Nursing, 1983-1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Society for Advancement in Nursing Newsletter, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Songs, 1999, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Space Allocations, Requests, etc., 1975-1977 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - State Board of Nursing: Establishing a New Nursing Program Pt. 1, 1973-1979 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - State Board of Nursing: Establishing a New Nursing Program Pt. 2, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - State Board of Nursing: Progress Reports to the Board, 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - State Board of Nursing Survey Visit, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)